<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type='text/xsl' href='/xml/xsd2html2xml/xsd2html2xml.xsl'?>

<recipe 
xmlns="https://cazzscookingcommunity.github.io" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="https://cazzscookingcommunity.github.io /xml/recipe.xsd"> 
                                                                                
    <title>Corner Store Curry</title>
    <filename>corner_store_curry.xml</filename>

    <comment>c/o Jamie Olivers with cazzie tweaks </comment>
    <thumbnail>../images/jamie_oliver_corner_store_curry.jpeg</thumbnail>
    <image></image>
    <category></category>
    <yield></yield>
    <prepTime></prepTime>
    <cookTime></cookTime>
    



    <ingredient>4-6 chicken thigh fillets</ingredient>
    <ingredient>2 TB spoons curry paste (what ever you have on hand)</ingredient>
    <ingredient>2 TBsp olive oil</ingredient>
    <ingredient>2-4 cloves garlic crushed </ingredient>
    <ingredient>4 inches ginger grated </ingredient>
    <ingredient>2 fresh chilli sliced (optional)</ingredient>
    <ingredient>2 TBsp curry paste (what ever you have on hand)</ingredient>
    <ingredient>1/4 cup mango chutney </ingredient>
    <ingredient>1 can of chopped tomatoes, chickpeas (rinsed and drained)  and coconut milk</ingredient>
    <ingredient>Any veggies you have on hand - chopped into 2-3 cm cubes</ingredient>
    <ingredient>Rice or grains to serve</ingredient>
    <ingredient>Serve with Roman lettuce if desired.</ingredient>

    <step>
Coat the chicken on all sides, with 1 TBsp curry paste and place back in fridge until ready to cook. 
Heat olive oil in a pot and add garlic, ginger and remaining curry paste. Cook for 3-5 minutes then add chopped tomatoes, coconut milk and chickpeas. Add the veggies and mango chutney, stir well to combine. Bring to a boil and reduce to a simmer and cook for 30 minutes. Cook rice or grains at this time if serving with your curry. 15 minutes before done cook the chicken in a little oil in a fry pan for 5 minutes each side. Remove form pan and rest for 5 minutes. 
Serve the curry on rice or grains, chilli sprinkle on top if you want it vegetarian. Serve on a plate with meat, grains and lettuce and lemon wedge and chilli sprinkled on top if desired. Easy and delish! This is one of those recipes that you can substitute, if you don’t have fresh ginger used dried or add left over veggies that you don’t know what to do with!
    </step>
</recipe>