<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipe 
xmlns="https://cazzscookingcommunity.github.io" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="https://cazzscookingcommunity.github.io ../xml/recipe.xsd"> 
                                                                                
    <title>ELIMINATION DIET_part3</title>

    <comment></comment>
    <thumbnail>../images/placeholder.png</thumbnail>
    <image></image>
    <category></category>
    <yield></yield>
    <prepTime></prepTime>
    <cookTime></cookTime>
    <part></part>



    <ingredient>Part 3</ingredient>

    <step>
Here is a suggested menu for you to follow.  It's a bit boring after week four, but it  will get you started.

Breakfast:
¼ - ½ cup cooked rice
¼- ½ cup rice milk
½ banana
¼ teaspoon stevia
Freshly grated nutmeg

Cook rice and rice milk in microwave for 1 minute.  Add the rest of the ingredients and stir well.

Snack:
Carrot and handful of cut up celery sticks and snow peas

Morning Tea:
One row of Plain Sakatas and Twinings peppermint tea (use any herb tea you like)
Piece of fruit if required

Lunch:
1 cup Rice Salad with small can of tuna in water.
Or leftover soup/ meal (from prepared menu)
Piece of Fruit

Afternoon tea:
2-3 Thin rice cakes with ½ avocado mashed on top with SandP
Or
Homemade beetroot dip (no lemon juice) with one row of plain Sakatas
Twinings peppermint tea (use any herb tea you like)
Dinner:
(Most recipes located on Cazz’s Cooking Community)

Monday-Vegetable Curry with rice

Tuesday-Pumpkin soup

Wednesday-Turkey burgers with Salad

Thursday-Cauliflower Soup

Friday-Fresh Fish fried in a little olive oil and sprinkled with SandP and freshly chopped dill.  Serve with salad (lettuce/ cucumber/ avocado/ grated carrot/chopped celery/ snow peas and ¼  cup extra virgin olive oil , 2 tbsp good quality vinegar, SandP.) 
 
Saturday-Lamb (any cut you prefer) sprinkled with cumin and SandP cooked in olive oil.  Served with roast veggies cooked in 2 tablespoons of olive oil- sweet spud/ parsnip/carrots/pumpkin/beetroot sprinkled with thyme and SandP. Served with something green, either steamed broccoli or snap peas, or chop vertically 8-10 baby bok choy and saute in fry pan with a little olive oil.  Sprinkle generously with SandP

Sunday- Vegetable Soup*
(*Chopped pumpkin butternut and another kind of pumpkin, cauliflower, swede, turnip, parsnip, carrot, celery and enough cups of broth to cover veggies. Bring to boil and reduce to a simmer.  Once pumpkin breaking apart and thickening add broccoli and frozen spinach and cook a further 10 minutes add SandP to taste.)

Sweet Treat:
If you feel like you need something sweet you can do the following:
Peeled and chop apples thinly and place in a shallow dish.  Place in oven on moderate heat with a little coconut oil, water, cinnamon and a sprinkle of Stevia.  Put in the oven until the apples become soft (about ½ hour.)

Everyday:
Drink 2-3 liters of water each day.

Suggestions to help:
Cook all soups and vegetable curry on weekend and freeze ahead- get out the meal you want the night before and place in the fridge to defrost.  Make a big pot of rice on Sunday and Thursday to cover you for each breakfast and Mondays dinner (You can used white rice for this, but cook brown rice for the rice salad.)  Have a big bag of carrot in the crisper and chop up an entire celery apart from two stems which you can use in the vegetable soup.  Place in an airtight container and  get out daily amount every morning- small snack bag.)
    </step>
</recipe>