<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type='text/xsl' href='/xml/xsd2html2xml/xsd2html2xml.xsl'?>

<recipe 
xmlns="https://cazzscookingcommunity.github.io" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="https://cazzscookingcommunity.github.io /xml/recipe.xsd"> 
                                                                                
    <title>Mint Slice</title>

    <comment>c/o Fresh Magazine with cazzie tweaks</comment>
    <thumbnail>../images/placeholder.png</thumbnail>
    <image></image>
    <category></category>
    <yield></yield>
    <prepTime></prepTime>
    <cookTime></cookTime>



    <part>
        <title>Base</title>
        <ingredient>125gms pitted dates chopped </ingredient>
        <ingredient>1/4 cup water</ingredient>
        <ingredient>250gm Scotch finger biscuits </ingredient>
        <ingredient>1/4 cup copha melted</ingredient>
        <step>Grease a dish approximately 18x26cm then place baking paper in it and set aside.</step>
        <step>Place dates and water in a small sauce pan and bring to boil then turn down low. Continuously stir until dates are soft and water absorbed. Take it of the heat and set aside. </step>
        <step>Break biscuits up and place in a blend. Whiz until fine crumbs, then do another whiz with cocoa added. </step>
        <step>Add date mixture and copha, mix until nicely combined. </step>
        <step>Tip into prepared dish and push down with your hands until flat. </step>
        <step>Place in freezer while you make the filling. </step>
    </part>

    <part>
        <title>Filling</title>
        <ingredient>350gms icing sugar sifted</ingredient>
        <ingredient>1 teasp peppermint essence</ingredient>
        <ingredient>4 drops green food colour (optional)</ingredient>
        <step>Pour icing sugar in a bowl and have metal spoon ready. </step>
        In a separate bowl place 3 TBsp boiling water, food colour and essence. Add to icing sugar and stir vigorously add an <step>another TBsp of boiling water if too thick. </step>
        <step>Pour over base and smooth it out. </step>
        <step>Place dish back in freezer while making the topping. </step>
    </part>

    <part>
        <title>Top</title>
        <ingredient>1/3 cup copha melted</ingredient>
        <ingredient>2 TBsp maple syrup or honey</ingredient>
        <ingredient>1/4 cup pure cocoa sifted</ingredient>
        <step>In a small saucepan melt copha. Once completely melted remove from heat and add maple syrup then cocoa. </step>
        <step>Stir well to remove any lumps. </step>
        <step>Pour over filling and this time place in fridge for 20 minutes. </step>
        <step>Remove from dish and cut into small squares. Store in fridge.</step>
    </part>

</recipe>