<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipe 
xmlns="https://cazzscookingcommunity.github.io" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="https://cazzscookingcommunity.github.io ../xml/recipe.xsd"> 
                                                                                
    <title>Quinoa filled eggplant</title>

    <comment>c/o Akis Petretzikis with cazzie tweaks</comment>
    <thumbnail>../images/placeholder.png</thumbnail>
    <image></image>
    <category></category>
    <yield></yield>
    <prepTime></prepTime>
    <cookTime></cookTime>


    <diet>GlutenFree</diet>
    <diet>Vegan</diet>

    <ingredient>3 Eggplants</ingredient>
    <ingredient>4 TBsp olive oil</ingredient>
    <ingredient>4 sprigs of thyme </ingredient>
    <ingredient>1 cup quinoa</ingredient>
    <ingredient>1 stock cube</ingredient>
    <ingredient>2 cloves garlic </ingredient>
    <ingredient>2 celery stalks chopped</ingredient>
    <ingredient>2 carrots grated </ingredient>
    <ingredient>1 TBsp fresh oregano </ingredient>
    <ingredient>1 can chopped tomatoes </ingredient>
    <ingredient>1 TBsp mint finely chopped</ingredient>
    <ingredient>salt and pepper</ingredient>

    <step>
Heat oven to 180C. Cut eggplants in half and score across flesh, and place on baking tray. In a small bowl mix 2 TBsp of olive oil, the leaves of the thyme sprigs and salt and pepper. Rub this all over eggplants and place cut side down on a baking tray and cook for 40 minutes. 
Meanwhile cook the quinoa. First rinse the quinoa under cold water. Drain and place in a pot.  Add two cups of water and then bring it to a boil. Place lid on pot lower to simmer. Cook until water absorbed, about 10-15 mins.
While quinoa is cooking heat oil in frying pan and add remaining olive oil. Add garlic and celery and cook until celery softened (about 5-8 mins.) Add chopped tomatoes, stock cube and carrot. Cook for a few minutes or until tomatoes juice reduces. Remove from heat and add oregano and quinoa and stir well. Remove eggplants from oven and scoop out flesh. Mix flesh with mixture and add salt and pepper to taste. Fill the eggplants evenly with mixed and serve with mint sprinkled on top. You can sever with side salad if desired. Absolutely delicious, looks fancy and easy to make!
    </step>
</recipe>