<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipe 
xmlns="https://cazzscookingcommunity.github.io" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="https://cazzscookingcommunity.github.io ../xml/recipe.xsd"> 
                                                                                
    <title>Spanakopita </title>

    <comment>c/o taste with cazzie tweaks </comment>
    <thumbnail>../images/placeholder.png</thumbnail>
    <image></image>
    <category></category>
    <yield></yield>
    <prepTime></prepTime>
    <cookTime></cookTime>
    <part></part>



    <ingredient>1/4 cup olive oil</ingredient>
    <ingredient>4-6 garlic cloves crushed </ingredient>
    <ingredient>1 bunch silverbeet or spinach</ingredient>
    <ingredient>1/2 bunch dill chopped </ingredient>
    <ingredient>250 gms feta cheese crumbled </ingredient>
    <ingredient>150 - 200 gms ricotta cheese </ingredient>
    <ingredient>3-4 TBSP Parmesan cheese grated </ingredient>
    <ingredient>1/2 teaspoon nutmeg</ingredient>
    <ingredient>12 sheets filo pastry fresh</ingredient>
    <ingredient>150-200 gms butter</ingredient>
    <ingredient>salt and pepper</ingredient>

    <step>
Preheat oven to 180C. Grease a small baking dish with butter and set aside. Wash silverbeet or spinach well and remove from stems and chop roughly. Leave to dry on a clean tea towel. Heat oil in large pan and cook garlic for about 3-5 mins. Add silverbeet and stir until it wilts. Turn off heat and add ricotta, feta, Parmesan, dill, nutmeg and salt and pepper to taste. Stir well until combined, leave mixture to cool. Next step you need to move quickly.  Lay a clean tea towel on the bench and then place fillo pastry on top. Then place another clean tea towel that has been wet but ringed really well and place on top of the pastry. Melt butter in microwave and brush the top pastry sheet generously. Gently place in dish (I usually fold mine in half as this fits my dish size well) and do the same for the next sheets until you have made 6 layers. Then scoop in the spinach mix and flatten with the bake of a spoon. Make a top layer the same as the base layer of pastry. You can use kitchen scissors to trim the edges if desired. Brush the top generously with butter and cook until golden brown (40-60 mins.) When done cut into slices and serve hot or cold.
    </step>
</recipe>