<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<?xml-stylesheet type='text/xsl' href='/xml/xsd2html2xml/xsd2html2xml.xsl'?>
<recipe xmlns="https://cazzscookingcommunity.github.io"
        xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
        xsi:schemaLocation="https://cazzscookingcommunity.github.io ../../xml/recipe.xsd">
  <title>Healthy Christmas Cake</title>
  <filename>healthy_christmas_cake.xml</filename>
  <thumbnail>healthy_christmas_cake.jpeg</thumbnail>
  <category>Sweets</category>
  <diet>GlutenFree</diet>
  <diet>Paleo</diet>
  <comment>c/o nourish every day </comment>
  <ingredient>500 gms mixed dried fruit </ingredient>
  <ingredient>3/4 cup walnuts chopped </ingredient>
  <ingredient>1 orange</ingredient>
  <ingredient>1 1/4 cup hazelnut or almond meal</ingredient>
  <ingredient>1/2 cup coconut </ingredient>
  <ingredient>1/2 teaspoon bicarbonate soda</ingredient>
  <ingredient>1/2 teaspoon salt </ingredient>
  <ingredient>3 teaspoon mixed spice</ingredient>
  <ingredient>1 teaspoon cinnamon </ingredient>
  <ingredient>5 eggs </ingredient>
  <ingredient>50 gms butter, melted</ingredient>
  <ingredient>1 teaspoon vanilla extract </ingredient>
  <ingredient>1/2 cup brandy</ingredient>
  <step>Remove 60ml from  brandy and set aside.</step>
  <step>Place the rest of the brandy in a bowl with all of the fruit.</step>
  <step>Place lid on top and let soak overnight (this can be done for up to a week and some people even do it for a month.</step>
  <step>You can also add additional brandy and stir every day.</step>
  <step>) Once fruit is soaked you can use it for your recipe.</step>
  <step>Line a grease a round cake tin and lime it with at least three layers of greaseproof paper.</step>
  <step>Make sure the paper come up out of the tin on around the sides.</step>
  <step>Preheat oven to 150C.</step>
  <step>Combine the hazelnut meal, coconut four, bicarbonate soda, salt, mixed spice and cinnamon in a large bowl.</step>
  <step>Zest the orange and add to the flour mixture with the walnuts (keep the orange.</step>
  <step>)
In a separate bowl whisk the eggs and add the melted butter vanilla and the squeezed orange juice.</step>
  <step>Create a well in the dry ingredients and add the wet ingredients.</step>
  <step>Mix until combined then fold through the drained mix fruit and chopped walnuts.</step>
  <step>Scoop into prepared tin and smooth down with a wet hand.</step>
  <step>Place in the middle rack of the oven and cook for an hour.</step>
  <step>Check every 1/2 hour to make sure it is not getting to brown.</step>
  <step>If getting too dark you can place some foil on top.</step>
  <step>Depending on your oven it may even take longer than an hour, if this is the case then you will need to turn the oven down to 140 or 130C.</step>
  <step>Remove from oven when skewer comes out clean.</step>
  <step>Pour the reserved brandy on top of the cake.</step>
  <step>Remove to a wire rack and cool completely in tin before removing.</step>
  <step>Once totally cool wrap totally in foil, keep in fridge.</step>
  <step>Curt slices as desired and wrap remainder in foil until all gone!.</step>
</recipe>
